Find us on:[](https://t.me/stingle_photos "Telegram")[](https://www.reddit.com/r/StinglePhotos/ "Reddit")[](https://github.com/stingle "Github")[](https://www.facebook.com/stinglephotos "Facebook")[](https://twitter.com/stingle_inc "Twitter")[](https://fosstodon.org/@stingle "Mastodon")[](https://f-droid.org/en/packages/org.stingle.photos/ "F-Droid")

[](javascript:void(0))

[](javascript:void(0))

Privacy Policy
==============

Thanks for entrusting Stingle Photos with your personal information. Holding onto your private information is a serious responsibility, and we want you to know how we're handling it.

### The short version

We only collect the information you choose to give us, and we process it with your consent, or on another legal basis; we only require the minimum amount of personal information that is necessary to fulfill the purpose of your interaction with us; we don't sell it to third parties; and we only use it as this Privacy Statement describes. No matter where you are, where you live, or what your citizenship is, we provide the same standard of privacy protection to all our users around the world, regardless of their country of origin or location.

Of course, the short version doesn't tell you everything, so please read on for more details!

### What information Stingle Photos collects and why

Information from website browsers

If you're just browsing the website, we don’t collect any information at all. Unlike other websites we don’t run analytics, we don’t keep any server logs, we don’t serve any third party content (like scripts) and we don’t run ads.

Information from Stingle Photos app users

If you create an account , we require some basic information at the time of account creation. You will create your own password, and we will ask you for a valid email address.

Why we collect this

* We may use your email address to confirm your email address and send you sharing notifications as well update you with important news. You can unsubscribe from any type of emails at any time and we will honor your request immediately.

Our legal basis for processing information

Under certain international laws (including GDPR), Stingle Photos is required to notify you about the legal basis on which we process User Personal Information. Stingle Photos processes User Personal Information on the following legal bases:

* When you create a Stingle Photos account, you provide your email address. We require this data element for you to enter into the Terms of Service agreement with us. If you have a paid account with us, there will be other data elements we must collect and process on the basis of performing that contract. Stingle Photos does not collect or process a credit card number, but our third-party payment processor (Google Pay, Apple Pay) does.

### What information Stingle Photos does not collect

If you're a child under the age of 13, you may not have an account on Stingle Photos. Stingle Photos does not knowingly collect information from or direct any of our content specifically to children under 13. If we learn or have reason to suspect that you are a user who is under the age of 13, we will unfortunately have to close your account. Please see our [Terms of Service](https://stingle.org/terms/) for information about account termination. Other countries may have different minimum age limits, and if you are below the minimum age for providing consent for data collection in your country, you may not use Stingle Photos without obtaining your parents' or legal guardians' consent.

### How we share the information we collect

We do not share, sell, rent, or trade User Personal Information with third parties.

We do not host advertising on Stingle Photos.

We do not disclose User Personal Information outside Stingle Photos, except in the situations listed in this section or in the section below on Compelled Disclosure.

We may share User Personal Information if we are involved in a merger, sale, or acquisition. If any such change of ownership happens, we will ensure that it is under terms that preserve the confidentiality of User Personal Information, and we will notify you on our website or by email before any transfer of your User Personal Information. The organization receiving any User Personal Information will have to honor any promises we have made in our Privacy Statement or in our Terms of Service.

Stingle Photos applications

You also have the option of using applications from Stingle Photos, such as our Desktop or Mobile app. All Stingle Photos applications are subject to this Privacy Statement, and we will always collect the minimum amount of User Personal Information necessary, and use it only for the purpose for which you have given it to us.

### What information do we have about you

* Email address
* Number of stored encrypted files
* Size of each stored file
* Creation date of each encrypted file
* Update date of each encrypted file
* Your current payment plan
* Payment history
* Number of devices that are currently logged in with your account
* Have you confirmed your email address or not

### How you can access and control the information we collect

Data retention and deletion

Generally, Stingle Photos will retain User Personal Information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services.

We may retain certain User Personal Information indefinitely, unless you delete it or request its deletion. For example, we don't automatically delete inactive user accounts, so unless you choose to delete your account, we will retain your account information indefinitely.

If you have a paid plan and you have stored more data than is allowed in a free plan and you fail to make a timely payment, your data may be deleted after 60 days. We will notify you to make a payment to retain your data.

### How Stingle Photos secures your information

Stingle Photos takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect User Personal Information from unauthorized access, alteration, or destruction; maintain data accuracy; and help ensure the appropriate use of User Personal Information.

Stingle Photos enforces a written security information program. Our program:

* aligns with industry recognized frameworks;
* includes security safeguards reasonably designed to protect the confidentiality, integrity, availability, and resilience of our users' data;
* is appropriate to the nature, size, and complexity of Stingle Photos business operations;
* includes incident response and data breach notification processes

In the event of a data breach that affects your User Personal Information, we will act promptly to mitigate the impact of a breach and notify any affected users.

Transmission of data on Stingle Photos is encrypted using SSH, HTTPS, and SSL/TLS. By design, your photos and videos information is encrypted prior to being transmitted to our servers and is therefore encrypted at rest.

### Stingle Photos global privacy practices

We store and process the information that we collect in the United States in accordance with this Privacy Statement. However, we understand that we have users from different countries and regions with different privacy expectations, and we try to meet those needs even when the United States does not have the same privacy framework as other countries'.

We provide the same standard of privacy protection — as described in this Privacy Statement — to all our users around the world, regardless of their country of origin or location, and we are proud of the levels of notice, choice, accountability, security, data integrity, access, and recourse we provide. We work hard to comply with the applicable data privacy laws wherever we do business.

Stingle Photos by design have no visibility on your photos and videos. They are encrypted on client side and only you have the keys to decrypt them. We store only encrypted blobs of data that CAN’T be deciphered both by us and any third party.

In particular:

* Stingle Photos provides clear methods of unambiguous, informed consent at the time of data collection, when we do collect your personal data using consent as a basis.
* We collect only the minimum amount of personal data necessary for our purposes.
* We offer you simple methods of accessing, correcting, or deleting the User Personal Information we have collected.

### How we respond to compelled disclosure

Stingle Photos may disclose information or other information we collect about you to law enforcement in response to a valid subpoena, court order, warrant, or similar government order. Because Stingle Photos by design encrypts everything with a key that only user has, disclosing information generally will be unusable (if you have sufficiently strong password or have chosen not to backup your keys).

### How we, and others, communicate with you

We will use your email address to communicate with you. For example, if you contact our support team with a request, we will respond to you via email.

Stingle Photos may occasionally send notification emails about new features, requests for feedback, important policy changes, or offer customer support. There's an unsubscribe link located at the bottom of each of the emails we send you. Please note that you can not opt out of receiving important communications from us, such as email confirmation, from our support team or system emails.

### Changes to our Privacy Statement

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Stingle Photos may change our Privacy Statement from time to time.

### Contacting Stingle Photos

If you have questions regarding Stingle Photos Privacy Statement or information practices, please feel free to contact us.

This Privacy Statement is available under a Creative Commons Zero license. Attribution to [GitHub, Inc.](https://github.com/) Changes have been made to the original content.

Find us on:

©2024 Stingle Photos Inc
